Elizabeth E. May Papers 1997.0119
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
- Series II: Employment, undated, 1918-1996
  - Subseries F: University Of Connecticut, undated, 1945-1988
    - Articles and Speeches
      - The Homemaker's 100-Hour Week, undated (Box 5, Folder 211)
      - I'm Married to a Working Mother, undated (Box 5, Folder 212)
      - Let's Listen to Youth, undated (Box 5, Folder 213)
      - Life Begins at 50, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 214)
      - Marriage and Family Living “Women and Work” V.23, 1961 November (Box 5, Folder 215)
      - New York State Dietetic and Home Economics Association
        - Correspondence, undated (Box 5, Folder 216)
        - Related Material for Speech, undated (Box 5, Folder 217)
        - Speeches, undated (Box 5, Folder 218)
      - Notes of Advice for Working Mothers, undated (Box 5, Folder 219)
      - Notes on Discussion of: Fitting a Volunteer or Professional Career into a Life-time Plan- Home Economics 101, undated (Box 5, Folder 220)
      - Outline for “Education of Women for Effective Citizenship”, undated (Box 5, Folder 221)
      - Research Issues Related to the Effects of Maternal Employment on Children, undated (Box 5, Folder 222)
      - Report of Michigan Conference on Problems of Employed Women, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 223)
      - “Report of the Committee on Federal Employment” President's Commission on the Status of Women, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 224)
      - The Role of Modern Woman, undated (Box 5, Folder 225)
      - Should Mother's Work?, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 226)
      - The Structural Effect on Consumer Dispersments of Wives Working, undated (Box 5, Folder 227)
      - What Every Teenager Should Know About Dating, undated (Box 5, Folder 228)
      - “What Role for Modern Woman” Platform, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 229)
      - Women's Education- articles and clippings, undated (Box 5, Folder 230)
      - Working Mothers... San Diego's Problem, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 231)
      - Working Wives and Mothers, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 232)
      - Working Women- bibliographies and articles, undated (Box 5, Folder 233)
    - Home Economic Extension Service
      - “Chinese Food and Traditions”, undated (Box 5, Folder 234)
      - “Delightful Recipes from the Four Corners of the World”, undated (Box 5, Folder 235)
      - “Entertaining With a Cosmopolitan Flavor”, undated (Box 5, Folder 236)
      - “French Foods and Traditions”, undated (Box 5, Folder 237)
      - “German Foods and Traditions”, undated (Box 5, Folder 238)
      - “Hungarian Foods and Traditions”, undated (Box 5, Folder 239)
      - “Lower Cost Meals that Please”, undated (Box 5, Folder 240)
      - “Metropolitan Cook Book”, undated (Box 5, Folder 241)
      - “Shortcuts for Modern Meals”, undated (Box 5, Folder 242)
      - “What's Cooking in Finland”, undated (Box 5, Folder 243)
      - “What's Cooking in France”, undated (Box 5, Folder 244)
      - “What's Cooking in Germany”, undated (Box 5, Folder 245)
      - “What's Cooking in Holland”, undated (Box 5, Folder 246)
      - “What's Cooking in Italy”, undated (Box 5, Folder 247)
      - “What Cooking in New England”, undated (Box 5, Folder 248)
      - “What's Cooking in Sweden”, undated (Box 5, Folder 249)
  - Handicapped Homemaker's Project
    - Speeches and Writings
      - “The Child Amputee and His Parents”, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 250)
      - A Manual for Training the Disabled Homemaker, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 251)
      - The Rehabilitation of Handicapped Homemaker -a selected bibliography..., 1967 (Box 5, Folder 252)
      - A Selected Bibliography on the Rehabilitation of Handicapped Homemakers, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 253)
      - Suggestions for the Rehabilitation of the Physically Handicapped Homemaker, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 254)
      - Text of Statement Summarized before the Congressional Hearing- New Haven, CT, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 255)
      - “Vocational Rehabilitation for Handicapped Homemakers”, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 256)
      - “Preliminary Suggestions Concerning the Rehabilitation of Orthopedically Handicapped Homemakers”, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 257)
      - “Suggestions Concerning Vocational Rehabilitation of Orthopedically Handicapped Homemakers, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 258)
      - “Vocational Rehabilitation Orthopedically Handicapped Homemakers”, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 259)
      - “Where There's A Will”, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 260)
      - “Who Should Rehabilitate the Handicapped Homemaker”, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 261)
      - Work Simplification in Child Care- Teaching Materials for Rehabilitation of handicapped Homemakers, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 262)
    - Research Material
      - Child Care Equipment for Physically Handicapped Mothers, undated (Box 5, Folder 263)
      - Clothes for the Physically Handicapped Homemaker, undated (Box 5, Folder 264)
      - Cornell Kitchen - Product Design Through Research, undated (Box 5, Folder 265)
      - “Easy Ways”, undated (Box 5, Folder 266)
      - Film Strips- “A Severely Handicapped Homemaker Goes Back to Work”, undated (Box 5, Folder 267)
      - The Functional Home for Easier Living, undated (Box 5, Folder 268)
      - Handicapped Homemakers, undated (Box 5, Folder 269)
      - The Heart of the Home, undated (Box 5, Folder 270)
      - Help for Handicapped Women, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 271)
      - Homemaking Hints- National Tuberculosis Association, undated (Box 5, Folder 272)
      - Make Work Easier, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 273)
      - A Manual for Training the Disabled Homemaker, undated (Box 5, Folder 274)
      - One-Armed Mother, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 275)
      - Pamphlets for Programs for/about Handicapped Homemakers, undated (Box 5, Folder 276)
      - Pamphlets on Taking It Easy, undated (Box 5, Folder 277)
      - Play Experiences Handicapped Mothers May Share with Young Children, undated (Box 5, Folder 278)
      - Proceeding: AHEA PreConvention Workshop Expanding the Services of the Home Economist in Rehabilitation, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 279)
      - Proceedings of the Workshop on the Rehabilitation of the Disabled Homemaker, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 280)
      - Work Simplification In the Area of Child Care for Physically Handicapped Women
        - Progress Report, 1955-1956 (Box 6, Folder 281)
        - Cover, Background, and Summary Statement for Final Report, undated (Box 6, Folder 282)
        - Summary of the Final Report, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 283)
        - Final Report, 1955-1960 (Box 6, Folder 284)
      - Rehabilitation of Handicapped Homemakers-Motion pictures, Slides, and Bulletins, undated (Box 6, Folder 285)
      - “A Report of the UConn Project on Child Care Problems of Physically Handicapped Mothers”, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 286)
      - Self-Help Clothing for Handicapped Children, undated (Box 6, Folder 287)
      - A Severely Handicapped Homemaker Goes Back to Work in Her Own Kitchen, undated (Box 6, Folder 288)
      - Sewing and House Cleaning Units for Cardiac Homemakers, undated (Box 6, Folder 289)
      - Suggestions for Physically Handicapped Mothers on Clothing for Preschool Children, undated (Box 6, Folder 290)
      - Take It Easy When Cleaning - pamphlet, undated (Box 6, Folder 291)
      - The Team Approach to the Rehabilitation of the Handicapped Homemaker, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 292)
      - Team Approach Workshop pamphlets and articles, undated (Box 6, Folder 293)
      - Where There's A Will- pamphlet, undated (Box 6, Folder 294)
      - You Can Do Laundry—With Hand Limitations - with script notes for Slide Series, undated (Box 6, Folder 295)
    - Scrapbook, undated (Box 11)
  - Study Abroad
    - Speeches and Writings
      - “ Finland Leads in Instructional in Homemaking Activities for Physically Handicapped Children”, undated (Box 6, Folder 296)
      - Homemaking Instruction for Handicapped Children -observations from visit to Finland, undated (Box 6, Folder 297)
      - Notes on European Visit, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 298)
      - Notes on Scandinavian Trip, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 299)
      - Romance and Gardening- notes on Rehabilitation in Homemaking gathered in Europe, undated (Box 6, Folder 300)
      - Contacts Made During Sabbatical Leave Study - rehabilitation in U.S. and Europe, undated (Box 6, Folder 301)
      - Bathroom Modifications for Disabled—Stockholm, undated (Box 6, Folder 302)
      - Bathroom Modification for Disabled— Sweden, undated (Box 6, Folder 303)
      - Clothing for the Handicapped— Sweden, undated (Box 6, Folder 304)
      - Correspondence from Amsterdam, Netherlands (with Diagrams), undated (Box 6, Folder 305)
      - Correspondence—foreign, 1968-1973 (Box 6, Folder 306)
      - Family Kitchen— Sweden, undated (Box 6, Folder 307)
      - French Articles and Pamphlets about Handicapped Persons, undated (Box 6, Folder 308)
      - Housing for the Disabled— Netherlands, undated (Box 6, Folder 309)
      - ICTA— Sweden—Aids for the Disabled, undated (Box 6, Folder 310)
      - Information on the Training Apartment—Stockholm, undated (Box 6, Folder 311)
      - Physically Handicapped Housewife—printed in Sweden, undated (Box 6, Folder 312)
      - Portugal Correspondence, undated (Box 6, Folder 313)
      - Quantitative Evaluation of the Activity of Back Muscles in Lifting— Denmark, undated (Box 6, Folder 314)
      - Rehabilitation in Canada, undated (Box 6, Folder 315)
      - Rehabilitation in Denmark, undated (Box 6, Folder 316)
      - Rehabilitation in Finland, undated (Box 6, Folder 317)
      - Rehabilitation of the Disabled Housewife Kings College Hospital—London, undated (Box 6, Folder 318)
      - Report on the Exhibition of Aids for the Disabled- Australia, undated (Box 6, Folder 319)
      - Research about Handicapped Children— Sweden, undated (Box 6, Folder 320)
      - Swedish and English versions—“Don't Give up Mother!”, undated (Box 6, Folder 321)
      - The Tensions of Home and Job— The Royal Bank of Canada, 1961-1963 (Box 6, Folder 322)
  - Homemaker Rehabilitation Exhibit
    - Labels for Pictures from International Exhibit, undated (Box 6, Folder 323)
    - Material from Exhibit, undated (Box 6, Folder 324)
    - Correspondence and Entrance Form from Stockholm
      - Australia, undated (Box 6, Folder 325)
      - Denmark, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 326)
      - England, 1960-1964 (Box 6, Folder 327)
      - Finland, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 328)
      - France, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 329)
      - Stockholm, undated (Box 6, Folder 330)
      - Sweden, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 331)
      - United States, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 332)
  - President's Committee on the Employment of the Handicapped
    - Appointments and Certificates, undated (Box 6, Folder 333)
    - “Consider the 'Labor Force' in the Home”, undated (Box 6, Folder 334)
    - Correspondence, 1978-1988 (Box 6, Folder 335)
    - Employing the Handicapped in the Home, undated (Box 6, Folder 336)
    - Guidelines for Compiling a Directory of Community Services in Rehabilitation/Employment of Handicapped Men, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 337)
    - Homemaker Rehabilitation before Committee, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 338)
    - Performance, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 339)
    - Rehabilitation for Independent Living, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 340)
    - Reports, Address, and unidentified materials, undated (Box 6, Folder 341)
- Series III: Books, undated, 1949-1991
  - Homemaking for the Handicapped
    - Bookcovers, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 342)
    - Foreword, undated (Box 6, Folder 343)
    - Form Letter from E. May about Buying Book, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 344)
    - Order Form, undated (Box 6, Folder 345)
  - Independent Living for the Handicapped and the Elderly
    - Contracts, Papers about, 1973-1988 (Box 6, Folder 346)
    - Review and Ad for, undated (Box 6, Folder 347)
    - Write-up/ Review, undated (Box 6, Folder 348)
    - Ad in fashionable for, undated (Box 6, Folder 349)
    - Credits for photographs and drawings, undated (Box 6, Folder 350)
    - Bibliographical and Informational Listing, undated (Box 6, Folder 351)
    - Addresses of Colleagues and Publishers for Research, undated (Box 6, Folder 352)
    - Rough Draft pp. 217-249, undated (Box 6, Folder 353)
    - Rough Draft pp. 250-271, undated (Box 6, Folder 354)
    - Correspondence- book and Co-authors, 1973-1989 (Box 6, Folder 355)
  - Subseries A: Speeches and Writings, undated, 1956-1971
    - “Child Care Problems of Physically Handicapped Mothers”, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 356)
    - Journal of Home Economics
      - Child Care Problems of Handicapped Mothers, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 357)
      - Handicapped Homemakers Now “Workers”, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 358)
      - Independent Living for the Disabled Homemaker, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 359)
      - Industrial Engineering Techniques Applied to the Problems of Homemakers with Physical Limitations, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 360)
      - International Conference on Homemaker Rehabilitation, undated (Box 6, Folder 361)
      - “A Letter to Mothers Who Are Disabled”, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 362)
      - Management Principles Applied to Homemaking, undated (Box 6, Folder 363)
      - “Non-Industrial Applications of Industrial Engineering”, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 364)
      - “Progress Since 1963” Future Directions for Home Economics In Rehabilitation- presented at AHEA Workshop, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 365)
      - “Rehabilitation of Handicapped Homemakers”, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 366)
      - Rehabilitation Views and Previews, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 367)
      - Remarks Made by Dr. May in Meeting of Woman's Committee, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 368)
      - Report on Research and Demonstration Projects from the field of Home Economics Relating to Rehabilitation in Area of Homemaking, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 369)
      - Research and Demonstration in Homemaker Rehabilitation, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 370)
      - “Suggestions for the Nurse in the Rehabilitation of the Handicapped Homemaker”, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 371)
      - “Value Looks Into the Future”-with Lillian Gilbreth, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 372)
      - “What Can the Nurse do to Help in the Rehabilitation of the Handicapped Homemaker”, undated (Box 6, Folder 373)
      - Work Simplification for Handicapped Homemakers, undated (Box 6, Folder 374)
      - “Work Simplification for Handicapped Mothers”, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 375)
      - “Work Simplification in Child Care for Physically Handicapped Mothers”, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 376)
      - Workshop on Home Management and Family Housing - Virginia Polytechnic Institute, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 377)
  - Subseries B: Subjects, undated, 1949-1991
    - Bathrooms
      - Bathroom Adaptations and Modifications for Disabled, undated (Box 7, Folder 378)
      - The Bathroom Criteria for Design, undated (Box 7, Folder 379)
      - Planning Bathrooms for Today's Homes, undated (Box 7, Folder 380)
    - Clothing
      - Clothing Illustrations- with page numbers and positions, undated (Box 7, Folder 381)
      - Clothing Illustrations II- with page numbers and positions, undated (Box 7, Folder 382)
      - Patterns for Clothes for Handicapped, undated (Box 7, Folder 383)
    - Elderly
      - A Checklist for Retirement Houses, undated (Box 7, Folder 384)
      - Designing Interiors for the Elderly: Furnishings/Lighting/ Color, undated (Box 7, Folder 385)
      - The Family of One, undated (Box 7, Folder 386)
      - Many Happy Returns, undated (Box 7, Folder 387)
      - Meals for One or Two, undated (Box 7, Folder 388)
      - Rehabilitation Literature- Furniture Design for the Elderly, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 389)
      - 65+ by Melvin Oss, undated (Box 7, Folder 390)
      - Where Did You Go? Nowhere..., undated (Box 7, Folder 391)
      - What Did You Do? Nothing..., undated
    - Handicapped Children
      - Articles on toys for handicapped children, undated (Box 7, Folder 392)
      - An Attainable Occupational Goal, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 393)
      - Children An Interdisciplinary Journal for the Professions Serving Children, 1964 January/February (Box 7, Folder 394)
      - Feeding the Child with a Handicap, undated (Box 7, Folder 395)
      - Growing Up- Cerebral Palsied Children Learn to Help Themselves, undated (Box 7, Folder 396)
      - How to Help Your Handicapped Child, undated (Box 7, Folder 397)
      - Let's Look at 4-H and Handicapped Youth, undated (Box 7, Folder 398)
      - On Being a Parent of a Handicapped Child, undated (Box 7, Folder 399)
      - The Preschool Exceptional Child, undated (Box 7, Folder 400)
      - Research on the Handicapped Child and the Family, undated (Box 7, Folder 401)
      - Self Help- Clothing for Children Who Have Physical Disabilities, undated (Box 7, Folder 402)
      - Some Questions and Answers on Occupational Therapy, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 403)
      - Suggestions for the Development of Natural History Programs in School for Handicapped Children, undated (Box 7, Folder 404)
      - Teachers of Crippled Children and Teachers of Children With Special Health Problems, undated (Box 7, Folder 405)
      - What Can be Done for the “Homebound Child?”, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 406)
      - “You Are Not Alone” - Help for Your Crippled Child, undated (Box 7, Folder 407)
    - House/ Building Design
      - Design of Buildings to Permit Their Use by the Physically Handicapped, undated (Box 7, Folder 408)
      - A Functional Home for Easier Living, undated (Box 7, Folder 409)
      - House Planning Aids- Dining Area, undated (Box 7, Folder 410)
      - Making Buildings and Facilities Accessible to and Usable by the Physically Handicapped, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 411)
      - Report on Dwellings for Disabled Persons, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 412)
      - Sewing and House Cleaning Units for Cardiac Homemakers, undated (Box 7, Folder 413)
      - Space Standards for Household Activities, undated (Box 7, Folder 414)
      - Wheelchair Houses-pamphlets, 1949-1961 (Box 7, Folder 415)
    - Kitchen Design
      - Beltsville Energy Saving Kitchen- Workrooms, undated (Box 7, Folder 416)
      - Cardiac Efficiency- Kitchen Training Manual, undated (Box 7, Folder 417)
      - How to Make Cupboard Storage Devices, undated (Box 7, Folder 418)
      - Kitchen in a Low Income Housing Project Adapted for a Paraplegic Homemaker, undated (Box 7, Folder 419)
      - Kitchens for Women in Wheelchairs, undated (Box 7, Folder 420)
      - “The Physically Handicapped and Kitchen Operation” by Julia S. Judson, undated (Box 7, Folder 421)
      - Planning Kitchens for Handicapped Homemakers, undated (Box 7, Folder 422)
      - Shaped Kitchen Arrangements - House Planning Aids, undated (Box 7, Folder 423)
      - Space and Design Requirements for Wheelchair Kitchens, undated (Box 7, Folder 424)
      - “Wheelchair Kitchen” Accent on Living, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 425)
    - Rehabilitation
      - A Conference on Research Needs in the Rehabilitation of Person's with Disabilities Resulting from Cancer, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 426)
      - The Disabled Homemaker: Organizational Activities, Family Participation, and Rehabilitation Success, undated (Box 7, Folder 427)
      - Future Directions for Home Economics in Rehabilitation, undated (Box 7, Folder 428)
      - “The Home Economist Participates” Notes for Rehabilitation Meeting Talk, undated (Box 7, Folder 429)
      - Leader's Workshop on Principles of Work Simplification Applied to Problems of Physically Handicapped Homemakers, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 430)
      - Rehabilitation of the Physically Handicapped in Homemaking Activities Proceedings of a Workshop, undated (Box 7, Folder 431)
      - Rehabilitation- The Way to Togetherness by Mary Switzer, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 432)
      - The Role of Home Economics Specialists in Rehabilitation of the Physically Handicapped -AHEA, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 433)
      - Syllabus of Rehabilitation Methods and Techniques, undated (Box 7, Folder 434)
      - Work Simplification for Handicapped Mothers, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 435)
    - Self Help for the Disabled
      - Do It Yourself Again Self Help Devices for the Stroke patient, undated (Box 7, Folder 436)
      - A Handbook for Your Recovery... with Exercises, undated (Box 7, Folder 437)
      - The Helping Hand, undated (Box 7, Folder 438)
      - Housekeeping Helps for the Handicapped Homemaker, undated (Box 7, Folder 439)
      - How to Get HELP if you are Paralyzed, undated (Box 7, Folder 440)
      - Rx for the Disabled House, undated (Box 7, Folder 441)
      - Self Help Adaptations for the Adult Cerebral Palsied, undated (Box 7, Folder 442)
    - Related Book Material
      - Accent On Living, 1968 Winter (Box 7, Folder 443)
      - Articles on Taking It Easy, undated (Box 7, Folder 444)
      - US Dept. of Justice- Civil Rights Division Title II, III Highlights (Disability Act), undated (Box 7, Folder 445)
      - Dept. of Justice- Federal Register, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 446)
        - -Nondiscrimination on the basis of disability... pets. III, IV, undated
      - Energy Used in Reaching Charts, undated (Box 7, Folder 447)
      - The Leaning Post Maryland Society for Crippled Children and Adults, undated (Box 7, Folder 448)
      - The New Jersey Conference on the Handicapped “Continuity of Community Services for the Handicapped”, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 449)
      - Out of the Shadows- the story of Muscular Dystrophy, undated (Box 7, Folder 450)
      - Outwitting the Therbligs, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 451)
      - The Physically Handicapped Housewife, undated (Box 7, Folder 452)
      - The Role of the Home Economist, Nutritionist, and Dietitian in Rehabilitation of the Physically Handicapped, undated (Box 7, Folder 453)
      - Speeches, Correspondence, and Program for American Public Welfare Association, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 454)
      - “Take It Easy” Washington State Heart Association, undated (Box 7, Folder 455)
      - Technology = Disability, University of Nebraska, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 456)
      - The Three Gifts of Life by Nellie M. Smith, undated (Box 7, Folder 457)
- Series IV: Related Materials, undated, 1955-1996
  - Subseries A: Writings Post-UConn, undated, 1971-1980
    - Clothing for Adults with Handicaps, On Your Own, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 458)
    - “Handicapped Children-`On Their Own'-Too” On Your Own, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 459)
    - “Independent Living for the Handicapped and Aging”, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 460)
    - “Men- On Their Own”, On Your Own, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 461)
    - “Not For Veterans Only”, On Your Own, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 462)
    - “Planning For Retirement”, On Your Own, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 463)
    - “Planning For Retirement”- notes and article from Health Value, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 464)
  - Subseries B: Subject Files, undated, 1955-1996
    - Articles and Notes for Elderly Research, undated (Box 8, Folder 465)
    - Articles on Home Design and Products for Handicapped, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 466)
    - Clothing/ Ready-Made Clothing for the Handicapped, undated (Box 8, Folder 467)
  - Correspondence- Rehabilitation in Homemaking, undated (Box 8, Folder 468)
  - Disability Prevention and Rehabilitation: A Global Challenge Conference, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 469)
  - Easter Seals
    - Catalog and Pamphlet on Resources for (Box 8, Folder 470)
    - People With Disabilities, undated
    - Rehabilitation Literature, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 471)
    - Hand Written Material, undated (Box 8, Folder 482)
  - Health Association of Broome County
    - Correspondence, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 472)
    - Notes and Speeches- “Address on the Rehabilitation of the Cardiac Homemaker”, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 473)
  - Home Health Care Resource Catalog- Sears, undated (Box 8, Folder 474)
  - India
    - Correspondence from India Trip, 1964-1965 (Box 8, Folder 475)
    - “Some Impressions of India Written by a Tourist from the US”, undated (Box 8, Folder 476)
  - KON Forum -KON Home Economics Forum, 1994-1996 (Box 8, Folder 477)
  - Land Conservation and the Environment -pamphlets, undated (Box 8, Folder 478)
  - Lillian Gilbreth -articles and correspondence, undated (Box 8, Folder 479)